A Guide to the Eva Kruger Architectural Papers, 1952-1965
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
The Eva Kruger Architectural Collection 1952-1965
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2000-098
1 box, 9 folders, 6.69 cu. ft.
The collection consists of biographical information, postcards, watercolor photographs, and architectural drawings for projects mostly in Germany.
Creator
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Eva Kruger Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections through multiple accessions in 2000- 2002.
Biographical Information
Eva Marianne Kruger was born in Berlin, Germany in 1922 and earned her architecture degree from the Technische Hochschule Charlottenburg in 1950. She worked as an architect in Germany until the mid 1960's when she then turned her focus to a career in art.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of one box with curriculum vitae, thesis project, postcards, watercolor photographs, a bound notebook, and 9 folders of architectural drawings of residences and hotels.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type.
Contents List
- Curriculum vitae, thesis (Box-folder 1:1)
- Postcards, watercolor photographs, bound writing "Hans Hinkelman" (Box-folder 1:2)
- Residence for Dr. Degen, 15 drawings, 1950 (Map-case 10:1:1)
- Ausftellungs Pavilions, 16 drawings, undated, Watercolors, 4 drawings, n.d (Map-case 10:1:2)
- Plans, sections and elevations for Friedhofskapelle, 6 drawings, 1965 (Map-case 10:1:3)
- Hotel by the sea, 7 drawings, 1965, Motel Anlage, 8 drawings, undated (Map-case 10:1:4)
- Residence for Gieorg Speyerst, 3 drawings, 1952, Residence for Max Regerstrauss, 6 drawings, 1954 (Map-case 10:1:5)
- Residence for Dr. Kurt Dallwig, 7 drawings, 1955, Residence for Am Rabenstein, 3 drawings, 1955, Residence in Aarburg, 6 drawings, 1955 (Map-case 10:1:6)
- Elevations for residence in Fulda, 5 drawings, undated, Residence for H. Weil, 1 drawing, 1957, Residence for M. Frauenlobstr, 1 drawing, undated (Map-case 10:1:7)
- Competition posters for a boys' school, 3 posters, 1953 (Map-case 10:1:8)
- Competition posters for a boys' school, 2 posters, 1953 (Map-case 10:1:9)